翻译  肉松
翻译  妖精希亚
翻译  小饭
翻译  沫沫
翻译  丶Charl
翻译  ET外星人
时间轴  Jessie
顾问  老杜
后期  饿得慌
校对  草草
总监  草草
第四季  第六集
纸牌屋
人人影视倾情奉献
梅瑞迪斯·李
卫生和人类服务部部长
安东尼·莫雷蒂弗兰西斯·安德伍德
波利跳
邓巴曾与古德温见面  承认见面  攻击总统
与俄罗斯达成救市协议
七国峰会
俄罗斯同意石油开采计划
杰·夏普
恭喜
发送至: 雷米·丹顿
雷米
中国提供40%的救市金
China provides 40% of the bailout,
国际货币基金组织再提供40%
the IMF provides another 40%
一个美中能源企业的联盟
and a consortium of American and Chinese energy companies
解决剩下的20%
tackles the remaining 20%,
我们以开采权作为交换
in exchange for which they get drilling rights.
美方只用拿出八千亿中的一千五百亿
The US would only have to contribute 150 of the $800 billion.
俄罗斯企业会监督生产
Russian companies would oversee production
获取一小部分收益
and get a slice of the revenues.
这些是拟开发区
These are the proposed development zones.
我们割让了开采权吗
We split the drilling rights?
是的  先生  中国出了更多钱
Yes, sir. China puts in more money,
我们就拿出我们的开采技术
but we contribute our drilling technology.
分享技术真的好吗
Should we really be sharing that?
他们早就想从我们这儿偷学了
They're already trying to hack it from us.
佩特罗夫同意了吗
Has Petrov agreed to this?
我打算在
I'm planning to propose
德国勃兰登堡的七国峰会上跟他提
it to him in Brandenburg at the G7 Summit.
我们已邀请俄罗斯和中国参加
We've invited Russia and China to attend,
但国会批准前
but we didn't wanna move forward
我们不想采取进一步行动
until we had congressional approval.
-鲍勃  -我们该私下谈
- Bob? - We should discuss privately.
你要亲自去勃兰登堡吗
You're going to Brandenburg yourself?
如果他的病情继续恶化
If his health continues to worsen--
之后再看情况
We'll assess as we get closer,
但如果情况悲观我就不去
but, no, I'll stay here if it looks dire.
我们应该起草拨款申请
We should probably draft an appropriation
以防需要举办国葬
in case we need to pay for a state funeral.
-道格  -部长女士
- Doug. - Madam Secretary.
我可以去白宫的
I could've come to the White House.
器官供应组织要听命于你
The organ network, it answers to you.
说对了一半  从监管方面来说...
Yes and no. Uh, in a regulatory capacity--
你有权力调整器官接受人名单
You have the power to modify the recipient list.
顺序由供应组织决定
That's up to the network.
他们有专家委员会...
They have an expert committee that--
总统的生命不能由一个委员会决定
The president's life isn't going to be decided by a committee.
我给你看点东西
Let me show you something.
他昨天是第三位  第一位已经移植了
He was number three yesterday. Number one got a transplant.
总统现在是第二位  他活的机会很大
Makes the president number two. His chances are very good.
但这个安东尼·莫雷蒂再过几小时就要死了
But this man, Anthony Moretti, he's just hours away from dying.
那就让他死
Then let him die.
我不会这么做的
I'm not doing this.
不仅违法  也有违道德
It's not just the law. It's the ethics--
那就改变你的道德标准
Then change your ethics.
不然你就辞职  让副部长打这个电话
Or you can resign, and your deputy can make this call.
如果他不愿意  那他也辞职
And if he won't, then he can resign, too.
我会把这个部门翻个底朝天  找到我需要的人
I will strip away this entire department until I find who I need.
打电话吧
Now make the call.
-好  我上去了  -你用过吗
- Okay, I'm on. - You ever use it?
不  我一般用谷歌
No, I use Google.
它市场份额很小
Uh, it's a small market share,
但一个月仍有数十亿次搜索
but still, it's billions of searches a month.
如果一个候选人有更多点击量
Now, what if a certain candidate got more hits,
排名更靠前
was ranked higher,
正面报道多过负面报道呢
more positive coverage favored over negative coverage?
如果那个候选人是威廉·康威呢
What if that candidate was William Conway?
操纵搜索结果  公众会与他们反目的
Manipulating searches? The public would turn on them.
帮他们拉到了上百万的选票
It gets them millions of votes.
能弄到确凿证据吗
Can you get me solid proof?
我不会参与这样的事
Well, I am not getting involved in something like this.
我只会作为朋友  给你友善的建议
What I will give you is advice as a friend.
别把一年的时光浪费在安德伍德夫妇身上
Don't waste a year of your life on the Underwoods.
他们已经输掉了竞选
They've already lost the election
而且自己还没有意识到
and they don't even realize it.
我知道你只是想帮忙
I know you're only trying to help,
也明白你肯定很担心
and I'm sure you must feel frightened
弗兰克的情况
about Frank's condition--
你没必要拐弯抹角  凯茜
You don't have to be delicate, Cathy.
我希望你不要干涉我的工作
I'd like you to let me do my job.
中国不能成为谈判的核心
China cannot be at the center of this negotiation,
雷蒙德·塔斯克也不行
or Raymond Tusk.
把石油公司牵扯进来
Involving the oil companies
是我们赢得共和党支持的唯一办法
is the only shot we have at winning Republican support.
还记得那次玩啤酒乒乓球  你放水让我赢吗
Do you remember when we played beer pong and you let me win?
我们两个就坐在那边
The two of us were sitting right over there,
那两张椅子上
in those two chairs,
你征求了我的意见
and you asked me for my advice.
那是一条好建议
It was good advice.
你也接受了  我不明白你现在为什么不肯接受
And you listened to it. I don't know why you won't now.
你上次提的是建设性意见  这次却不是
You were proposing a way forward. This time you're not.
与你不同  我是由参议院委任的
Well, unlike you, my nomination was confirmed by the Senate,
因为他们相信我知道自己在做什么
because they believed I knew what I was doing.
很抱歉  克莱尔  但在我看来
Forgive me, Claire, but it seems to me
你正在利用现在的局面  行使一些
that you are taking advantage of the situation to assert authority
-你无权行使的权力  -凯茜
- you don't have a right to assert. - Cathy,
弗兰西斯现在不在
you don't have Francis right now.
我是你的最佳选择
I'm the best thing you've got,
请与我共同解决这个问题吧
so please work with me on this.
国会不会批准的
Congress will never approve this.
你在浪费大家的时间
You're just wasting everybody's time.
共和党会支持的
The Republicans will get in line.
不是共和党  是民主党
Not the Republicans, the Democrats.
我跟杰姬·夏普谈过
I spoke to Jackie Sharp.
当她得知是你制定了这个计划...
When she heard you developed this plan...
她是个厉害的女人  克莱尔  而且很有说服力
She's a formidable woman, Claire, and very persuasive.
-雷米·丹顿  -雷米  我们得谈谈杰姬
- Remy Danton. - Remy, we need to talk about Jackie.
多美的夜晚
Such a nice night.
我们出去走走吧
Let's go somewhere outside.
你想去哪
And where do you wanna go?
带我去海湾吧
Take me to the bay.
我们去裸泳
We'll go skinny-dipping.
你不是只有几个小时时间吗
I thought you only had a couple hours.
我可以找到借口的
I'll make up some excuse.
我在酒店待腻了
I'm sick of hotel rooms.
咱俩明天还有事呢
We both got a big day tomorrow.
你怎么这么扫兴
Why are you being no fun?
因为你要搅黄我的法案
Because you're trying to kill my bill.
你不是想见我  你是来游说我的
You didn't wanna see me. You wanted to lobby me.
-杰姬  -是谁告诉你我反对的
- Jackie, listen. - Who told you I was against it?
博奇的幕僚长
Birch's Chief of Staff.
我相信你能从中捞到不少钱  但是...
Well, I'm sure you stand to make a lot of money on this, but--
不是因为钱
It's not about the money.
克莱尔不是靠钱说服你的吗
Isn't that how Claire convinced you?
我今晚不想谈
I just wanted to leave it tonight.
我不想冲你发火
I didn't wanna be mad at you.
我只想
I just wanted...
我不明白你为什么要帮她
I don't understand why you're helping her.
你得让博奇同意
You've gotta get Birch on board.
安德伍德夫妇欺骗过我
The Underwoods have lied to me,
利用过我  还试图威胁我
they've used me, they've tried to intimidate me.
我不知道克莱尔想干什么
I don't know what Claire's up to,
但我决不会坐以待毙
but I'm not gonna let it happen without a fight,
而且国务院都已经反对了
not with the State Department against it.
克莱尔知道了
Claire knows.
我们俩的事
About you and me.
她有我们的照片
She got photographs
多次同时离开同一家酒店
of us leaving the same hotel at the same time, multiple occasions.
送我回我车上
Take me back to my car.
-杰姬  听我说  -请掉头
- Jackie, listen... - Turn around now, please.
所以我最近没怎么联系你
It's the reason I haven't been in touch.
我想保护你...
I wanted to protect you...
-但是她提出了  -我不想谈这个
- but she's making-- - I don't wanna talk about it.
停车  让我下去  或者送我回去
Just stop the car and let me out or drive me back.
我送你回去
I'll take you back.
再一两天
A day or two.
我们没法提前知道  总统先生
We might not have much warning, Mr. President.
肝脏如此接近衰竭
When the liver is this close to failure,
一切都有可能突然发生
things can happen suddenly.
你们应该做好准备
You should be prepared.
-他的手是怎么回事  -那是扑翼样震颤
- What's happening with his hands? - It's called asterixis.
当身体无法排除氨时就会发生这种情况
It happens when the body can't clear ammonia.
谢谢你  撒克逊医生
Thank you, Dr. Saxon.
我不去勃兰登堡了
I'm not going to Brandenburg.
不  你必须去
No, you have to.
-凯茜会代表我谈判  -在这事上我不信任她
- Cathy will negotiate on my behalf. - I don't trust her on this.
我们必须冒这个险
That's a risk we'll have to take.
我不能冒的险  是总统去世时我在海外
The risk I won't take is being overseas if the president dies.
我们都不知道国会
We don't even know if Congress
会不会批准救市计划的拨款
will approve the appropriation for the bailout.
他们会批准的  我会确保他们批准
They will approve it. I'll make sure they do.
你现在不该担心这个  克莱尔
You shouldn't be worrying about this now, Claire.
你应该全心关注弗兰克
You should be focused on Frank.
我们得给他上呼吸机
We need to put him on the ventilator
保护他的呼吸道
to protect his airways.
您该走了  夫人  去休息一下
You should go, ma'am. Go get some rest.
-现在不是时候  莉安  -非常紧急
- Now's not a good time, LeAnn. - This can't wait.
-怎么了  -波利跳
- What is it? - Pollyhop.
-搜索引擎吗  -康威在跟他们合作
- The search engine? - Conway is working with them.
他们可以操纵人们搜索的东西
They can manipulate what people search for.
给了他们巨大优势
It gives them a huge advantage--
等等  慢点  这是什么意思
Wait, slow down. What does this mean?
意思是我们输了
It means that we lose.
康威的名字  他的照片
Conway's name, his image,
他们可以控制人们看到什么  强迫人们看
they can control what people see. They can force-feed it.
即便他们不那么做
Even if they're not doing that,
即便他们只是在追踪用户  也足以打败我们了
even if they're just tracking users, it's enough to beat us.
你知道人们在搜索什么  就知道一切
You know what people are searching for, you know everything,
他们的希望  恐惧
their hopes, their fears,
他们半夜盯着天花板时
what they're thinking about when they're staring at the ceiling
脑袋里在想什么
in the middle of the night.
-谁告诉你的  -我信任的人
- Who told you this? - Someone I trust.
我现在不能处理这件事
I can't deal with this right now.
我们得想点办法  克莱尔  否则大选
We have to do something, Claire, or the election--
莉安  我丈夫刚刚痉挛发作
LeAnn, my husband just had a seizure.
恐怕都不能竞选了
There may not even be an election.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry. I--
如果弗兰西斯挺过来了  我们到时再处理
If Francis survives, we will deal with this then.
现在  我需要全心关注我眼前的事
Right now, I need to focus on what's right in front of me.
没有任何犯罪行为
There was no criminal wrongdoing.
这我们理解  但为什么要冒险呢
That we can fathom. But why take the chance?
因为保持沉默会让我看上去有罪
Because pleading the Fifth makes it look like I broke the law.
我同意
I agree.
我会说出真相  我会承认
So I'll tell the truth. I'll own it.
是的  你没有跟他见过面
Yes, that you didn't meet with him.
你是说...
Are you suggesting that--
司法部长和希瑟各执一词
It's the Attorney General's word against Heather's.
作为你的律师  我不能参与这个对话
As your lawyer, I can't be part of this conversation.
我们还是能赢得竞选的
We can still win this campaign.
我去大厅等你
I'll be in the lobby.
我会支持你的说法
I'll back you up.
安保人员只看见我和古德温一起
The security detail only saw me and Goodwin together,
没看见你和他
not the two of you.
我要宣誓作证的
This is under oath.
安德伍德的人是想抹黑我们
Underwood's people are trying to smear us.
这场竞选的全部意义
The whole point of this campaign
就是做与安德伍德截然不同的人
was to be the opposite of Underwood.
我以为你想要这个的
I thought you wanted this.
如果要犯法就不行
Not if it means breaking the law.
你觉得换作他  还会有这种犹豫吗
Do you think he'd even be having this conversation?
你是真正在意法律的  希瑟
You actually care about the law, Heather...
所以该由你来做总统
which is why you need to be president.
-安德伍德夫人  -鲍勃  我不知道...
- Mrs. Underwood. - Bob, I didn't realize--
少数党领袖和我正在讨论救市计划
The Leader and I were just discussing the bailout package.
布莱斯总统要我强调一下
President Blythe just wanted me to stress
民主党人当前团结一致的重要性
how important it is that the Democrats stick together right now
弗兰西斯还在...
with Francis being--
不必如此
There's no need.
我刚给议长打了电话  安排紧急投票
I just called the Speaker to schedule an emergency vote.
我相信总统会很满意的
I'm sure the President will be pleased.
-弗兰克怎么样  -他还撑着
- How's Frank? - He's hanging in there.
你一定想快点回医院
I'm sure you wanna get back to the hospital.
但谢谢你亲自前来
But thank you for making the personal visit.
牵挂和祈祷与你同在  克莱尔
Thoughts and prayers, Claire.
谢谢你  鲍勃
Thank you, Bob.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
失陪一下  领袖
Excuse me, Leader.
你是来威胁我的
You came here to threaten me.
我们不必不和的  杰姬
We don't need to be at odds, Jackie.
你打算每次遭遇我的反对
Do you plan on hanging this over my head
都拿这个来威胁我吗
every time I try to oppose you?
你自己不小心  可怪不得我
You can't fault me for your sloppiness.
也就是"是"了
That's a "Yes."
只要我们是一边的
As long as we're working together,
你就没什么可担心的
you have nothing to worry about.
总统先生  希望您别过于乐观
Mr. President, I wouldn't get your hopes up.
七国集团的成员们
The members of the G7
已经因为邀请了俄罗斯而不满了
are already ruffled because Russia was invited,
而佩特罗夫可能会利用这个机会
and Petrov may be using this opportunity
在国际社会上给我们难堪
to embarrass us in front of the international community.
什么事
Yes?
-第一夫人来了  先生  -请她进来
- The First Lady is here, sir. - Send her in.
先生  我想先完成我们的讨论
Sir, I would like to finish our briefing--
第一夫人想见我  我可不能让她等着
I'm not gonna keep the First Lady waiting if she wants to see me.
-你听说了吧  -对  博奇几分钟前来电了
- I'm sure you've heard. - Yes, Birch called a few minutes ago.
我想和你一起去勃兰登堡  凯茜
I'd like to join you in Brandenburg, Cathy.
很感谢你愿意出力
Well, I appreciate you wanting to pitch in,
但我真的认为没这必要
but I really don't think that's necessary.
我比任何人都了解这个计划
Well, I know this plan better than anyone.
-总统先生  -机会只有一次
- Mr. President... - There is only one shot at this.
-所有人都在场  -弗兰克呢
- Everyone at the same table. - What about Frank?
我在勃兰登堡能派上用场  在这里就不能了
In Brandenburg, I can be useful. I can't here.
第一夫人不能
The First Lady cannot
代表美国政府进行谈判
negotiate on behalf of the United States government.
谁做代表由你决定  总统先生
The delegation is at your discretion, Mr. President.
有人支持你  或许是好事
It might be good for you to have some support.
她的在场会削弱我作为国务卿的权威
Her presence undermines my authority as Secretary of State.
凯茜  佩特罗夫非常固执  这你相信我
Cathy, Petrov is incredibly stubborn. Trust me, I know.
你为什么不愿意用上所有的资源呢
Why wouldn't you wanna have every asset available to you?
请允许我做这件事  总统先生
Allow me to do this, Mr. President.
-先生  -如果能增加胜算
- Sir-- - If it increases our chances.
会的  我保证
It will, I promise.
那就一起吧  我们把简报过一遍
Then join us. We're going over the briefing now.
你尽力了  弗兰克
You tried, Frank...
这已经比大多数人都强了
which is more than most people ever do.
现在  只剩下我们了
Right now, it's just us.
闭上你的眼睛
Rest your eyes.
我们有用不完的时间
We have all the time in the world.
丹尼  发生什么事了
Danny, what was that?
-丹尼  -没事  妈妈
- Danny? - Nothing, Mom.
把门打开
Open the door.
安德伍德夫人  萨克逊医生的电话
Mrs. Underwood? Dr. Saxon is on the line.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
喂
Hello?
晚上好  或者说早上好
Good evening, or good morning.
安德伍德总统正在准备手术
President Underwood is currently being prepped for surgery
接受肝脏移植
to receive a liver transplant.
不出意外的话
Barring any complications,
手术将耗时12到13小时
the surgery is expected to take 12 to 13 hours.
有需要的话我们会向大家更新情况
Uh, we'll update you about the progress if need be,
但在手术结束之前应该不会有什么消息了
but probably nothing more until the operation's completed.
我们可以马上让飞机掉头  夫人
We can turn the plane around right now, ma'am.
你能在他手术结束之前赶回去
You'll be back before he's out of surgery.
我们应该那样做  克莱尔
We should do that, Claire.
峰会我会迟到  但是大家能
I'll be late to the summit, but everyone will--
不  我们马上就到了
No. We're almost there.
-我们继续前进  -说实话  克莱尔
- We keep going. - Honestly, Claire--
-告诉机长保持航线  -是  夫人
- Inform the captain to stay on course. - Yes, ma'am.
请给我接赛斯·格雷森
Connect me with Seth Grayson, please.
他已经进去了
He's already gone in.
第一夫人在去勃兰登堡的路上
The First Lady is currently en route to Brandenburg
手术期间不会回到华盛顿
and will not be in Washington for the surgery.
她会继续按计划
She will continue onto the G7 Summit
在七国峰会中协助杜兰特国务卿
to assist Secretary Durant, as planned.
她让我宣读以下声明
She asked me to read the following statement.
"不调头对我来说是个困难的决定"
"It was a difficult decision for me not to return..."
但我了解我的丈夫  如果他醒着
But I know my husband. If he were conscious...
"他会让我继续前行"
"...he'd tell me to press on..."
因为支持他最好的方式就是为国效力
...that the best way to be at his side is to serve my country.
"而我在德国能比在等候室里发挥更大的作用
"And I can serve it better in Germany than in a waiting room.
如果有紧急情况  我会马上回去"
If there's an emergency, I'll return immediately..."
但我对杰弗逊纪念医院的
...but I have the utmost faith...
"医疗团队有极大的信心"
"...in the medical team at Jefferson Memorial."
我在祈祷手术成功
I'm praying for a successful procedure,
我也请求你们跟我一起为我丈夫
and I ask all of you to join me in praying for my husband,
你们的总统祈祷
your president.
请就坐  邓巴女士
Right over there, Ms. Dunbar.
你的律师会来参加吗
Will your attorneys be joining us?
我已经让我的律师不要来了
I've asked my attorneys not to attend.
我们得说明  为您的利益考虑...
We have to advise you that it's in your best interest--
我很清楚  摩根先生
I'm well aware, Mr. Morgan.
我不是第一次坐上这张桌子了
It's not my first time at this table.
谢谢  周主席  佩特罗夫总统
Thank you, President Zhou. President Petrov?
俄罗斯和中国一样希望参与国际峰会
Russia shares China's desire for inclusion.
我们期待展开有成效的会谈
We are looking forward to productive talks.
同时我们也要对安德伍德总统的手术
And we also want to extend our sincere best wishes
致以最真诚的祝福
for President Underwood's surgery.
我们都非常想念他
He is dearly missed at this meeting.
谢谢  总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
我们可以开始了吗
So, shall we begin?
当务之急是
The most pressing order of business
国际货币基金组织以及美国和中国
is the joint IMF, American-Chinese debt relief package
对俄联邦的债务减免计划
to the Russian Federation.
在录吗
We're recording?
邓巴女士  你所作的任何陈述
Ms. Dunbar, any statement you make
都将记入司法部报告  成为公共记录
will be part of the public record as part of the DOJ report.
虽然这段录像只是为了...
Although this video is simply for purposes of...
你可以把录像传给媒体
You can make the video available to the media.
我没有什么好隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
你是要放弃对大众保密的权利吗
So you're waiving your right to keep the video from public view?
是的
I am.
司法部长说你曾向她施压
The attorney general says you pressured her
要她追查卢卡斯·古德温的说法
to look into Lucas Goodwin's claims--
我读过司法部长的陈词
I've read the attorney general's statement.
我们还得到一份来自一名年轻女性的证词
We also have a deposition from a young woman,
是一名职员  她说古德温
a staffer, who says Goodwin
在3月8日辛辛那提的一场活动中曾假扮志愿者
posed as a volunteer at an event in Cincinnati on March 8th.
你与古德温先生会过面吗
Did you meet with Mr. Goodwin?
我在每场活动上都要与上百人握手
I shake hundreds of people's hands at every event.
如果他去过辛辛那提  我有可能跟他握过手
If he was in Cincinnati, there's a chance I may have shaken his.
但要说我跟他曾单独会面...
But the claim that he and I met one-on-one...
所以你是说你没有见过他吗
So you're saying you didn't meet with him?
我们有电话记录  邓巴女士
We have phone records, Ms. Dunbar.
你的确曾与司法部长通过话
You did speak to the attorney general.
玛莎是我的前任上司和老友
Martha is my former boss and an old friend.
我们经常通话  她为什么要说我...
We speak frequently. Why she would claim that I...
我们要个简单的回答  邓巴女士
We need a simple answer, Ms. Dunbar.
你是否曾与
Did you or did you not
卢卡斯·古德温在辛辛那提私下见面
meet with Lucas Goodwin privately in Cincinnati?
是的
Yes.
我与一名不认识的男人见了面
I met with a man I didn't know
结果发现他精神错乱
who turned out to be unhinged.
我联系司法部长
I contacted the attorney general
是因为她是国内顶尖的执法人员
because she's the top law enforcement official in the country
而且证人保护计划受她管辖
and WITSEC is under her jurisdiction.
我没做错什么
I did nothing wrong.
告诉我们这场会面的性质
Tell us the nature of this meeting.
我要郑重声明
I'd like to say, for the record,
我认为这次面谈是一场政治阴谋
that I think this interview is an act of political sabotage.
其目的就是要通过关联让我看上去有罪
Its goal is to make me look guilty by association,
但表象与事实是两回事
but there are the way things look and the way things actually are.
我调查弗兰克·安德伍德的时候
When I investigated Frank Underwood,
他看上去是清白的  但他并不是
he looked innocent, but he wasn't.
我无法证明  可我知道确实如此
I couldn't prove it, but I knew it to be true.
邓巴女士
Ms. Dunbar...
你们有我跟古德温先生会面的证据
You have proof that I met with Mr. Goodwin.
我已经承认了
I've admitted it.
这只能证明我的诚实
All that proves is that I'm honest,
不像总统那样为了个人利益
unlike a president who would use the Department of Justice
利用司法部去攻击他的对手
to target his political opponent for his own personal gain.
我要提醒你  女士
Let me remind you, ma'am,
总统在这次调查开始前就已陷入昏迷...
the president was unconscious when this investigation began...
不论他是否意识清醒
It doesn't matter whether he was unconscious or not,
不论他是死是活
whether he lives or dies.
为总统效力的人代表的就是他
The president is the people who work for him.
我觉得这事成不了
I don't think this is going to work.
佩特罗夫在会上说得漂亮
Petrov's talking the talk in session,
但却不肯跟我私下见面
but he won't meet with me privately.
中国人已经准备签字了  如果是因为这个
Chinese are ready to sign, if that's the hold-up.
跟中国人无关
It's not the Chinese.
他拒绝跟任何非国家首脑讲话
He refuses to meet with anyone other than a head of state.
那就看看他愿不愿意跟总统夫人见面
Then see if he'll meet with the president's wife.
这不能改变他道德败坏的事实
It doesn't change the fact that he is morally corrupt,
他也败坏了听命于他的机关
and he has corrupted the institutions that report to him.
所以我才要竞选总统
That is why I am running for president,
因为总得有人跟他抗争
because someone needs to fight this.
她不止跟古德温见了面
So not only did she meet with Goodwin,
她还利用调查来攻击
she's using the investigation to attack
这会儿正在手术台上的总统
a president who's on the operating table as we speak.
是啊  她一直为自己辩护
Yeah, the way she keeps defending herself
只会让阴谋论者有更多...
only gives conspiracy theorists more...
她完了
She's done.
我不是说她有参与...
Now, I'm not saying that she was involved...
毫无疑问
Without a doubt.
...但许多人正在社交媒体上...
...but many are taking to social media...
-赛斯  -你好  辛西娅
- Seth. - Hello, Cynthia.
你有没有什么工作给我
Think you might have anything for me?
...尤其总统的支持率还...
...and certainly not a president whose approval rating...
在你们的竞选团队里
On your campaign?
是的  很讽刺
Yeah, it's ironic...
我得挂了  祝你好运
I'm gonna hang up now. Good luck.
但我觉得她是搞砸了
...but I think she may have just tanked it.
总统先生  移植手术完毕
Mr. President... the transplant's complete.
他们正在缝合刀口
Now they're closing him up.
接下来就看他能否适应新器官了
We'll see how he accepts the new organ.
也许我们该给克莱尔打个电话了
Maybe we should try and get Claire on the phone.
嗯
Yeah.
快了  我们在等他
Soon. We're waiting for him now.
好的  好  谢谢  唐纳德
Okay. Okay, thank you, Donald.
-挺顺利喽  -除非他的身体排斥这个肝脏
- So it's going well? - Well, unless his body rejects the liver.
-总统先生  -安德伍德夫人
- Mr. President. - Mrs. Underwood.
总统先生
Mr. President.
我以为我们要单独见面
I thought we were meeting alone.
作为政府的代表
As the administration's representative,
我需要参与到所有谈话中
I need to participate in any conversations--
国务卿女士  我相信我的人说得很清楚了
Madam Secretary, I believe my people were very clear, hmm?
能给我们点时间吗  凯茜
Would you give us a moment, please, Cathy?
一小会儿就好
Just a little while.
我就在外面
I'll be outside.
手术进展怎么样
So... how is surgery going?
目前还好
So far, so good.
你一定累坏了  快坐吧  坐吧
Ah, you must be exhausted. Now, sit. Sit.
你一定更想在医院里吧
I imagine you'd rather be at the hospital.
这事太重要了
Well, this is too important,
你又不肯跟杜兰特国务卿谈判
and you weren't going to negotiate with Secretary Durant.
你凭什么认为我会跟你谈判
What makes you think I'll negotiate with you?
那不是我们坐在这里的原因吗
Oh, well, isn't that why we're sitting here?
也许我只是想...再看到你的脸
Maybe I just wanted to... see your face again.
也许我喜欢你这张脸
Maybe I'm fond of it.
你是个美丽的女人  安德伍德夫人
You are a beautiful woman, Mrs. Underwood, hmm?
那双唇
Those lips...
你能为我说句话吗
Would you say something for me?
你可以说...
Would you say, um...
"你真可耻  总统先生"吗
"Shame on you... Mr. President."
当真吗  维克多  要重提那段不快吗
Really, Viktor? Are we gonna dredge that up?
道个歉就行
An apology would do...
如果你想谈判的话
if you want to negotiate...
如果我道歉  你就不会再尊重我了
Well, you would lose respect for me if I apologized.
没错
Yes.
这倒是
Yes, this is true.
我不是来旅游的  维克多
I'm not here for a sightseeing trip, Viktor.
弗兰西斯需要一个肝脏  我需要救市
So, Francis needs a liver and I need a bailout.
-你需要什么  -我需要你同意那些条款
- What do you need? - I need for you to agree to the terms.
对啊  条款  没错
Oh, yes, the terms. The terms, yes.
但你为什么在这儿  而不是陪着弗兰西斯
But why are you here... and not with Francis?
你母亲生病时  你回到了她身边
When your mother is sick, you go to her.
现在却不在你丈夫身边
Not your husband, hmm?
那些报道是真的吗
Were the stories true?
出问题了吗  克莱尔
Are there problems, Claire?
你对中国的顾虑是什么
What are your concerns with the Chinese?
有太多钻井在敏感地区
There are too many drilling sites in sensitive areas.
对我们是个安全问题
It's a security issue to us.
你们具体担心的是哪几个钻井
And what sites, in particular, are you worried about?
你熟悉各个区域吗
Oh, you... you are familiar with the individual zones?
这是我的计划  我完全清楚
It's my plan. I know it backwards and forwards.
这样啊  怪不得对你这么重要
I see, so that's why it's so important to you.
因为这是你的
Because it's yours.
是这其中之一吗
Is it one of these?
在太平洋海岸上
On the Pacific coast?
您找我  先生
You asked for me, sir?
我想尽快离开这里
I wanna get out of this place as soon as possible.
我会安排的  先生
I'll make sure of it, sir.
克莱尔在哪
Where's Claire?
她在德国
She's in Germany.
德国
Germany?
我很多事要向您汇报  总统先生
A lot to catch you up on, Mr. President.
-雷蒙德  -中国人开始担心了
- Raymond. - The Chinese are getting skittish.
他们想知道为什么这么慢
They wanna know why it's taking so long.
如果佩特罗夫不尽快同意  他们可能会退出
Now, if Petrov doesn't agree soon, they may back out.
-谢谢  雷蒙德  -我随时待命
- Thank you, Raymond. - I'm on standby.
我们得马上达成协议
We need to shake hands on this.
不行  我告诉过你了  库页岛上不能有
No. No, I told you, nothing on Sakhalin Island.
只要南端两个区  你就可以救市了
It's two zones on the southern end. Then you have your bailout.
这样会打开一扇我不想开的门
It opens a door I don't want to open.
他们的要求很合理了  总统先生
They're being more than reasonable, Mr. President.
合理  谁说的
Reasonable? In whose eyes?
你们和中国在掠夺西伯利亚
You and China are raping Siberia.
不是我们把你们的经济搞砸的
We didn't run your economy into the ground.
是你自己
You did.
迈克尔·科里根上吊前
Is this how you tried to convince Michael Corrigan
你就是这么劝他的吗
before he hung himself?
因为你现在就是在要求我这么做
Because that's what you are asking me to do,
在我自己的脖子上系个绳套
to tie the noose around my own neck.
接下来呢  黑海吗  北极吗
What's next? The Black Sea? The Arctic?
我不能允许中国船只
I cannot allow the Chinese ships
这么靠近我的领土
to come this close to my sovereign--
安德伍德夫人  安德伍德总统打来找您
Mrs. Underwood, President Underwood is on the line.
-他醒了吗  -是的  夫人
- He's awake? - Yes, ma'am.
去吧  我们谈完了
Go, go. We're done here.
-我现在没空跟他通话  -安德伍德夫人
- I can't speak with him right now. - Mrs. Underwood--
我有空时会告诉你的
I will let you know when I'm available.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
你应该跟你丈夫通话
You should talk to your husband.
不达成协议  我不会离开这里的
I'm not leaving here until we have an agreement.
但你是个业余选手  克莱尔
But you're an amateur, Claire.
你飞过来  挺起胸脯
You fly in, you puff up your chest
假装自己是总统
and you pretend to play president.
但没了你丈夫  你又算什么呢
But what would you be without your husband?
什么也不是  只是张漂亮脸蛋
Nothing. A pretty face.
那好吧  你想演总统就演吧
So, yes, play the president if you like.
去吧  告诉中国人他们在太平洋上什么也得不到
Go. Tell the Chinese they get nothing on the Pacific.
你觉得你做得到吗  安德伍德夫人
You think you can do that, Mrs. Underwood?
你的人民正在受苦
Your people are hurting.
最多六个月  他们就会去红场游行
Six months at most, they're gonna be marching on Red Square.
我不想再给你留面子了
I'm done letting you have your dignity.
事实上  你就是个跪着的乞丐
The truth is you're a beggar on your knees,
我们逼你吃什么  你就得吃什么
and you will take whatever we shove down your throat.
维克多
Viktor.
接受协议  挽回面子
Take the deal. Get your dignity back.
国务卿女士
Madam Secretary.
61和67区联合控制权
Joint control of zones 61 and 67.
我们已取得协议  只等总统同意
We've got an agreement, pending the president's approval.
他在睡觉了
Well, he's sleeping now.
他们即将把他转移回白宫
They're moving him back to the White House soon.
-他看起来怎么样  -我只简单跟他聊了几句
- And how did he seem? - I only talked to him briefly,
但是医生说器官...目前情况良好
but the doctors say the organ is... taking well so far.
他们估计很快能恢复
They're expecting a quick recovery.
你做得非常好  总统先生
You've done an outstanding job, Mr. President.
-你也是  克莱尔  -我要去休息一会儿了
- So have you, Claire. - I'm going to try and get some rest.
当然  一路平安
Of course. Have a safe flight.
专家原本对本次峰会
Experts were pessimistic that
能否取得实质性成果并不乐观
anything meaningful could come out of the summit.
议长办公室送来的预算案草案
Draft of the appropriations bill from the Speaker's office.
请放在桌子上吧
Just put it on the desk, please.
凯瑟琳·杜兰特在勃兰登堡如是说
...Catherine Durant had this to say from Brandenburg.
佩特罗夫总统和我与中国政府
President Petrov and I worked through the night
通宵协商
in concert with the Chinese government
以达成协议
in order to come up with an agreement.
连同私营企业一起
Along with partners in the private sector,
美国  中国和俄罗斯将进行合作
the United States, China, and Russia will collaborate on a plan
在东西伯利亚未开发地区开采石油
to extract oil from untapped sites in eastern Siberia.
这将使石油市场和全球经济
This will then enable a return to a more stable oil market,
重归稳定
as well as a stable global economy.
为使这项计划可行
Now, in order to make this plan viable
并减轻美国和
and mitigate any tax burden...
中国纳税人的税收负担
...to the American and Chinese taxpayers,
私营公司将提供大部分投资
the corporations will provide the bulk of the investment,
以及开采石油的基础设施和技术
the, uh, infrastructure to extract the oil and the technology.
所得利润
and then any of the profits
也将在这些公司之间
will then be distributed commensurately among
对应分配
these corporations, as well,
还包括俄罗斯政府投资的土地价值
and including the land value invested by the Russian government.
现在  我愿意接受任何提问
So at this time, I'd like to open the floor to any questions.
有很多人问我第一夫人扮演了什么角色
I'm getting a lot of questions about the First Lady's involvement.
我们就坚持说  她只是过去协助
We stick to our message that she was just there to assist.
杜兰特国务卿才是主导
Secretary Durant led the effort.
有很多报道说她和佩特罗夫开了很长的会
There's multiple reports that she and Petrov had a long meeting.
他们不过是互相问候  就这样
They greeted each other. That's it.
那我们否认吗
So we deny?
总统还未批准这个方案
The President hasn't approved the plan yet.
我们要关注他的康复  而不是...
We wanna focus on his recovery, not the-
-什么事  -卫生部长找您  先生
- Yes? - Secretary of Health for you, sir.
我回头去你办公室找你
I'll find you in your office.
部长女士
Madam Secretary.
-我刚给你发了邮件  -稍等
- I just sent you an email. - Hold on.
这是什么
What is this?
看见照片上的父亲了吧
The father you see there?
那就是我们为总统挤下去的人
That's who we bumped for the President.
他一小时前去世了
He died an hour ago.
留下两个孩子和他深爱的妻子
Father of two, loving husband.
马上从你的发件箱删除
Delete it right now from your outbox.
已经删了  但我想让你看到他的脸
I already did, but I wanted you to see his face...
和他留下的亲人
the family he left behind.
可能需要几天时间  但我...
Well, uh, it will probably take a few days, but, uh, I'm--
我太太起来了
My wife is up.
谢谢  先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
-安德伍德夫人  -安德伍德夫人
- Mrs. Underwood. - Mrs. Underwood.
克莱尔
Claire.
你痛吗
Are you in a lot of pain?
忍得了
Nothing I can't handle.
密查姆怎么样
Meechum?
我和他母亲联系过了
I spoke to his mother.
-弗兰西斯  别...  -帮我起来
- Francis, don't... - Help me up.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的  这对康复有好处
Yes. It's good for the recovery.
医生的吩咐
Doctor's orders.
他们要我每天至少下床一次
They want me on my feet at least once a day.
我们走走吧
Let's take a walk.
看看我行不行
Now, let me see if I can do it.
我得缓一缓
I need a minute.
我会批准你的方案
I'm going to approve your plan.
那方案很棒
It's a good plan.
很不容易
It was hard.
比我预想的还要难
Harder than I thought it would be.
留在我身边吧
Stay with me.
我们一起对付他们  一直如此
It's us against them. Always.
不然还有什么意义呢
Otherwise, what's the goddamn point?
我不能  弗兰西斯
I can't do it, Francis.
我不能回来再做第一夫人了
I can't come back and be First Lady.
不是这样
Not that.
我之前在总统办公室  说没有我你什么也不是
I said you were nothing, in the Oval, without me.
应该反过来才对
It's the other way around.
必须要有所改变了
It would have to be different.
我知道
I know.
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm saying.
来吧  看你能不能走到大厅尽头
Come on. Let's see if you can make it to the end of the hall.
在过去一年中  由于伊斯兰国(ISIS)势力扩大
巴黎遭到大规模恐怖袭击
在反恐的共同目标下  美国和俄罗斯的合作有升温的迹象
以美国国务卿克里为代表的美方官员
多次就反恐和叙利亚问题同俄方代表会谈
虽然会谈气氛远谈不上友好  但也非剑拔弩张
双方都希望在反恐方面有些建设性的合作
但整体上  俄罗斯仍然处于强势地位
出兵叙利亚后  他们一边打击伊斯兰国
但更多时间也在打击美方支持的反政府武装
俄军战机每天呼啸而过
美军不得不将地面特种部队的战略位置告之俄军  以免遭误伤
过去一年中  奥巴马不止一次在国际会议上同普京碰面
双方有过几次面对面的会谈
但从媒体报道及新闻图片上很容易看出  两人关系仍然十分紧张